If living near the lake has been on your
dream list, whether that's boating,
hiking, fishing, just catching sunsets
over the lake, or maybe you want a
little more space and nature, Lake
Belton has some of the best communities
in all of Central Texas. Today, I'm
taking you on a tour of some of the top
communities to consider if you're
looking for that lake lifestyle. I'm
talking beautiful communities, highly
rated school districts, access to all of
the amenities, and everything that
Temple Belton has to offer. Let's get to
it.
Hey, and welcome back to Living in
Central Texas. I'm Andrea Dudik, your
real estate expert and relocation guide
here in the Central Texas area. Took a
couple weeks off to have a baby, but now
I'm back and I've been dying to do a
video on Lake Belton and all the
surrounding communities. So, if you have
been considering moving to Belton,
Texas,
um or you've been curious about lake
living in the area, you are going to
want to watch this video. As you can see
behind me, this is one of the
communities. It's almost completely
built out, but really beautiful. You've
got some lake views, and I just can't
wait to show you. So, let's go.
Okay, friends, we are going to check out
Morgan's Point Resort, some of the best
communities.
Um I'm headed from my office, but if we
were to go left right here, up West
Adams, we would be about 3 minutes away
from all of the major retail on West
Adams. You know, talking Starbucks. I
say that first cuz I have caffeine
addictions. Um
but you've got, you know, your Walmart,
a bunch of great restaurants,
right up West Adams, and then it Oh, we
turned right, so now we're headed west
on West Adams.
And we're just minutes away from
Morgan's Point Resort and all of the
awesome communities that I'm about to
show you.
Um you can check out my video on
living in Temple, Texas
to kind of see
everything up West Adams.
And then if we were to stay on this and
go all the way up, we would get to
Temple Park which when you check out my
video Pros and Cons of Belton, Texas
you can see Temple Park and it's really
neat cuz you can sit at the benches and
wade in the water. And then right here
is Lakewood Elementary School, highly
rated elementary school. Uh one of my
kiddos goes there and I really
personally love it. Uh but
there's a very good chance that if you
were to be in Morgan's Point and you had
a kiddo in elementary, they'd be at
Lakewood.
We can already see all of the trees that
are starting to pop up. A big selling
point to
Morgan's Point is the mature trees, the
space, the privacy. We are coming up to
Morgan's Point Road and if you go left,
you go right over
Lake Belton.
So super super close to Lake Belton and
again straight, you're still at Lake
Belton but you're just you go to Temple
Park.
Morgan's Point Resort falls in Belton
within the city of Belton.
Over here on the left we have a new
Uncommon Pies, it's a new pizza spot.
You have Point Fitness
little special
unique workout facility that just opened
up. Well then one of the first
communities I'm going to show you is
right here which is Lago Terra.
I don't believe they are currently
building any more in Lago Terra in terms
of new construction, but the homes in
here are new. So, if you're looking for
newer construction
and you love this community, we can
often find homes for sale in here. But,
you can see there are really great size
lots. You've got half to 3/4 acre lots,
the mature trees.
You're not technically in Morgan's Point
in here, but you're basically touching
it, so I like to include it. You can go
through those gates over there and well,
I guess we could go that way.
To me,
this is uh if you go all the way back,
there are homes on the lake.
Carothers was the major builder in this
community. They also did build some
custom homes, a lot of custom homes, not
Carothers, but other builders just
randomly in this community as well.
Or you're going to hear my
my little baby making some noises in the
back as I show you guys around.
I took a minute off to have that baby,
but I'm back.
Kind of fun, we did a surprise gender
reveal
cuz we have two girls
and we had a third girl.
She is amazing.
But, woo, three girls, we're in for it.
Okay. So, if you see up front here as we
head through this gate, how beautiful is
this? You can see all of these homes
right here in this back section of Lago
Terra have a lake view. So, super super
super pretty.
So, we are still headed up Morgan's
Point Road just outside of Lago Terra.
This might look a little bit familiar if
you watched my video on Rancho Del Lago.
Cuz now we are in Morgan's Point. So, if
you're looking for a lake living, you
don't have to be in Morgan's Point.
There are some communities on the
opposite sides of Lake Belton, which
would be maybe Dawson's Ranch,
Regatta Oaks, and then some more older
established communities on that side.
So, some really good options there. And
then of course, um Stillhouse Lake
deeper in Belton,
um off of I-14. Those are separate
communities. Three Creeks is a really
fantastic one if you're looking to be
near Stillhouse Lake, um but that can be
another video for another time. So, we
are currently in Rancho Del Lago. Now,
Rancho Del Lago is zoned for Lake Belton
High School, North Belton Middle School,
and I believe High Point Elementary. So,
if you were interested in this
community, I could verify
all of that for you, but very similar
feel to Lago Terra.
Here's really interesting. You're going
to have a variety of resale homes,
which are still newer, as well as new
construction. So, they are still
building in this community. They have
spec homes, which of course means, you
know, you already started homes.
Um they've already made the selections.
They picked the lots.
And remember you're always going to get
a better on those spec homes because the
builders are trying to offload their
inventory
and
stop paying money on them. Um so, we can
really get you a much better deal on
those, but these homes, the spec homes,
are in in and around that 900,000 plus
price point.
Beautiful luxury builder. I really love
this community. I did that full video on
Rancho Del Lago just because I love this
builder and this community so much.
You can still pick a lot and build with
this builder and pick from their floor
plans, pick from their design
selections.
And that's a really fun process, too.
This builder did did just win the Parade
of Homes, which for our area is where
they showcase different builders and all
of their beauty and then remember that
if you are building new construction or
sorry, if you are buying or building new
construction, definitely contact me
because those sales reps, they are
really wonderful and kind. They do
represent the builder. So, they are not
going to typically represent your best
interest.
And they're not going to tell you about
all the negotiations and cool things
that we can get for you. And I do have a
lot of people relocating here that have
to purchase sight unseen, which can be
super, super, super scary. Good news is
is
technology is amazing. I can do video
for you. And I can FaceTime you. I can
upload them to Google Drive so that you
can
click on a link and look at them and I
can put that along with all of the, you
know, the floor plans, helpful
information, standard features, which is
going to tell you what comes standard in
a community.
Uh, you know, do they do spray foam
insulation? Is there an HOA?
Is uh,
do they do does the builder include like
what are their warranties and standard
build outs? All of the lots inside of
this community are half acre plus.
Plus, they did a really great job of
maintaining and keeping these gorgeous
oak trees on the lots. That's something
that's really, really, really hard to
find is
communities and that are are able to
keep all of those trees.
Here you are near Lake Belton and also
you can see from this big blue water
tower Morgan's Point. You are in
Morgan's Point. That's near, but you are
in Morgan's Point.
If we go right, here you are at Lake
Belton High School is just 1 minute
that way.
You have Dollar General right up here on
your right for for easy access
to grocery items or necessities when you
don't want to go to the grocery store,
which even that is 15 minutes away, so
no big deal.
You have a liquor store.
Cajun Crawfish Express, which gets
They do not They don't all They're not
always open,
but they have so many people and there's
just lines going to that place. I'm not
a crawfish person, but it is pretty
popular.
And then you have
Backyard Barbecue, which is amazing.
And on the left Sol De Jalisco's Mexican
Restaurant number four. They are a
chain. They are
Yes, they're a chain, but they are
great. I've had way too much Jaliscos
and
Backyard Barbecue cuz this is my neck of
the woods as well. So now we're sort of
headed into just
resale communities in Morgan's Point. A
lot of these streets are not
master-planned communities.
Got to find a good one to take you down.
Actually, I'll take you down the main
street that leads you through the
Morgan's Point What is that called?
Their community center?
Like city hall?
Holly Oaks on the right is a established
community out here, really pretty homes.
And then we also have Sabreonte up here
on the right as well.
If you ever call me and any of these
communities really jump out to you, I
can actually search for you by
subdivision.
If one just
spoke to you, you know?
In the morning and evenings, you'll see
deer just crossing the street. We have
tons of deer out here. The only
community that I can think of
in kind of Temple-Belton where you get
the deer roaming
the neighborhoods.
Oh, I was supposed to turn there. What I
get?
Better turn around.
Oh, I see some deer right now. Let's go
check these fellas out.
So, it is currently 2:30 in the
afternoon.
I'm taking you down a random street in
Morgan's Point.
And it's going It's going to the
restroom. All of Morgan's Point is on a
peninsula. We are surrounded by water
out here.
So, every
Every bit of an angle, even if you can't
see water, you are very close to water.
If you're open to older homes or you
want something maybe a little more
unique, you can drive through these
older streets of Morgan's Point.
This one's for rent, but you'll find
cute traditional homes.
>> Morgan's Point Resort,
City Hall
is right there.
Lake Belton in general is an Army Corps
of Engineers lake built in 1954.
It spans over 12,000
acres with more than 130 miles of lake
shoreline.
Known for fantastic bass and catfish
fishing.
We have caught a ton of parks around
here.
Cedar Ridge, Chalk Ridge, Winkler. On
the right, we have Cliff House, which is
our only
condos, and those are on the water.
Those actually don't come open, in my
opinion, that often.
And then, this is my favorite park. I
rave about it. This is Claypso Park.
They have a newer section here. It's for
toddlers ages 2 to 5.
You'll see deer walking around here,
too. And then, you have the older side
of the park right here, which I'll turn
around and show you. And then, they have
a community pool, which is open during
the summer, and you can get a pool pass.
But, you can see all this has a
beautiful lake view.
And then, they also have a basketball
and tennis court.
It's really sweet. During the holidays,
they'll have events down here. They'll
have um pictures with Santa, holiday
events.
Now, if you've been considering the
Austin, Texas area and somehow found
your way to this page,
we are about an hour north of Austin,
Texas.
Much lower traffic compared to many
Austin suburbs.
Even if you are living near the lake,
you are still 10 to 15 minutes away from
a grocery store at any given time. So,
how awesome is that? You can have that
more rural and peaceful
feel while still having great access to
all amenities.
Today, I showed you the more established
communities like this one,
the established streets, the Morgans
Point I showed you, Lago Terra inside of
Belton, just outside of Morgans Point,
Rancho del Lago, and
you do have those other communities on
the other side of Lake Belton, which
would be
uh Dawsons Ranch, Northcliff is a cute
one, Regatta Oaks.
And then, if you are open to lake living
not on Lake Belton or not by Lake
Belton, there's still Stillhouse Hollow
Lake.
And I think the most popular community,
it's a massive massive master-planned
community, is Three Creeks. I will
probably at some point do a whole other
video on Three Creeks.
It has
so many different builders I can think
of
I don't know, five to seven different
builders that build in that community,
from a variety of entry level to luxury.
And
they are also offering really great
incentives in that area. You can check
out Three Creeks online, and then if you
would like to know what sort of
incentives you can get, how the builders
work, time frames, if you want
information on inventory, I can get all
of that for you. And it doesn't cost you
anything to work with an agent. Uh all
of those builders do pay for you to have
representation. So, you So, definitely
utilize that to your advantage. So, on
the right, you have Rogers Park. That
backs to the park with boating access,
and then there's a bunch of marinas
around here and other access points.
This final community is absolutely
beautiful. It's the Cliffs at Lake
Belton. It's at the end of Morgan's
Point Resort and it is super secluded,
tons of trees, tons of wildlife, and a
large portion of it does actually
overlook the water.
And it is all surrounded by the Corps of
Engineer, so uh no neighbors surrounding
you if you purchase here. There are I
would say about a dozen to 15
custom-built homes in this community.
One is currently for sale as a resale,
it's a Mediterranean-style home, and the
other one coincidentally is another
Mediterranean-style home built by that
same builder
for sale brand new.
Aside from the already built homes that
might eventually go for sale again,
there are another 12 to 15 lots that are
currently being built on by a builder
who purchased up those remaining lots
from the developer. There are
unfortunately no lots for sale to build
your own custom, but if you're
interested in this community, we can
always get with this builder to see what
are available as a spec home, an already
started home by them, as well as maybe a
semi-custom on one of their remaining
lots.
Some of the things I really love about
this community is because a bunch of
these internal lots were built by
different developers, there's just a ton
of varying style and elegance in this
community.
You can see a lot of variation in the
architecture,
and everything is just very elegant and
stunning. If you are interested in
purchasing in this community, you're
looking probably in the upper 800,000s
over 1 million to purchase.
Okay, that's it for today. I hope you
enjoyed this tour of some of these
awesome communities near Lake Belton,
and if you like this video, you might
want to head on over to my YouTube page
where I have a full video on Morgan's
Point Resort and another video touring
Rancho Del Lago, which is one of the
communities we briefly drove through
today.
And if you're relocating to the Central
Texas area, you can find all my contact
information below. I'd love to be your
guide. You can also head on over to
livinginctx.com
where I have some fantastic resources
for relocating to Central Texas. Till
next time.